(Screaming)
Oh!
(Groaning and screaming)
(Panting) Ah!
Doug?
Honey, are you all right?
You were dreaming. Doug?
Was it about Mars?
- Is that better?
- Hmm.
My poor baby.
This is getting to be an obsession.
Was she there?
Who?
The one you told me about.
The brunette.
Oh, Lori.
I can't believe you're jealous of a dream.
- Who is she?
- Nobody.
"Nobody"? What's her name?
- I don't know.
- (Laughs)
- Tell me!
- I don't know!
You better tell me!
It's not funny, Doug.
You dream about her every night.
And I'm always back in the morning.
Let me go!
Come on, baby.
You know you're the girl of my dreams.
You mean it?
You know I do.
I'll give you something to dream about.
(TV) 'The chairman defended the attack,
saying that space-based weapons
'are our only defence against the
southern block's numerical superiority.
'And more violence last night on Mars
'where terrorists demanding independence
'once again halted the extraction
of terbinium ore.'
(Gunshots and screams)
'Kuato and his so-called freedom brigade
'claimed credit for this latest bombing,
'which attempted to reopen
the sealed-off Pyramid Mines.
'Mars military restored order
with minimal use of force
'and all damage to the strategic facility
was repaired within hours.'
(Man) 'No cameras!'
'With one mine already closed,
Mars administrator Vilos Cohaagen
'vowed that troops
would be used if necessary
'to keep production at full capacity...'
No wonder you're having nightmares.
You're always watching the news.
- Lori.
- Doug?
- Let's do it.
- Do what?
Move to Mars.
Honey, why do you have to spoil
a perfectly wonderful morning?
Just think about it.
Sweetheart, we've been through this
a million times. You'd hate it on Mars.
It's dry, it's ugly, it's boring.
I mean, really, a revolution could
break out there any second.
Cohaagen says it's just a few extremists.
You believe him?
OK. Forget about it.
'Absolutely not. Mars was colonised by
the northern block at enormous expense.
'Our entire war effort
depends on their terbinium.
'It's ridiculous to think we'd give it away
just because some lazy mutants...'
Doug.
- Maybe we should take a trip.
- Lori, move, please.
'...you've closed the Pyramid Mine
because you found alien artefacts?'
There's a lot better places than Mars.
What about Saturn?
Don't you wanna see Saturn?
(Cohaagen) 'I wish we could find
some artefacts.
'Our tourist industry could use a boost.'
(Lori) Everybody says that its gorgeous.
'Fact is, it's Mr Kuato and his terrorists
who spread these rumours
'to undermine trust in the government.'
We could take a long space cruise,
the kind with nothing to do.
- (Reporter) 'Have you found Kuato yet?'
- 'We don't even know what he looks like.'
- What do you say?
- I'm late, Lori.
Sweetheart. Doug.
I know it's hard being in a new town,
but let's give it a chance, OK?
Lori, don't you understand?
I feel like I was meant
for something more than this.
I want to do something with my life.
I want to be somebody.
You are somebody.
You're the man I love.
Bye.
Have a nice day.
(Tannoy) 'You are now entering
a safety zone.
'No unauthorised weapons allowed
beyond this point.
'You are now entering a safety zone.
'No unauthorised weapons allowed
beyond this point.'
(TV) 'Would you like to ski
but you're snowed under with work?
'Do you dream of a vacation
at the bottom of the ocean,
'but you can't float the bill?
'Have you always wanted
to climb the mountains of Mars...
'...but now you're over the hill?
'Then come to Recall Incorporated
'where you can buy the memory
of your ideal vacation
'cheaper, safer and better
than the real thing.
'So don't let life pass you by.
'Call Recall
for the memory of a lifetime.'
| 'For the memory of a lifetime
| 'Recall, Recall, Recall'
(Drilling)
Harry.
- Harry! You ever hear of Recall?
- Recall?
Where they sell those fake memories.
Oh, Recall!
(Sings) Recall, recall, recall!
- Thinking of going there?
- I don't know. Maybe.
- Well, don't.
- Why not?
A friend of mine tried one of their special
offers, nearly got himself lobotomised.
No shit?
Don't fuck with your brain, pal.
It ain't worth it.
I guess not.
(Drilling)
(Beeps)
Hello.
Good afternoon.
Welcome to Recall.
Douglas Quaid.
I have an appointment.
- Bob?
- 'Yeah?'
- Doug Quaid is here to see you.
- 'I'll be right out.'
OK.
That'll be just one minute, Mr Quaid.
Thank you.
(Beeps)
- Doug! Bob McClane. Good to see you.
- Nice to meet you.
Come on in. Through here.
Go and have a seat.
Make yourself comfortable.
- Thank you.
Now, help me out here, Doug.
- You were interested in a memory of...
- Of Mars.
Yeah. Mars.
- Is there a problem?
- Uh...
To be perfectly honest with you, Doug,
if outer space is your thing,
you'd be much happier
with one of our Saturn cruises.
Everybody raves about them.
No. I'm not interested in Saturn.
I said Mars.
OK. You're the boss.
Mars it is.
Now, let me see.
The basic Mars package
will run you 899 credits.
Now, that's for two full weeks
of memories, complete in every detail.
If you want a longer trip, that'll cost you
more cos it's a deeper implant.
What's in the two-week package?
When you go Recall, you get nothing
but first-class memories.
Private cabin on the shuttle, deluxe suite
at the Hilton, all the major sights:
Mount Pyramid, the Grand Canals
and of course, Venusville.
But how real does it seem?
- As real as any memory in your head.
- Come on. Don't bullshit me.
No. I'm telling you, Doug.
Your brain will not know the difference.
And that's guaranteed or your money back.
What about the guy you lobotomised?
Did he get a refund?
You're talking ancient history.
Nowadays, travelling with Recall
is safer than getting on a rocket.
Check out those statistics.
Besides, a real holiday
is a pain in the butt.
You got lost luggage, lousy weather,
crooked taxi drivers.
When you travel with Recall,
everything is perfect.
So, what do you say?
- All right.
- Smart move.
All right,
while you fill out this questionnaire,
I'm going to familiarise you
with some of our options.
No options.
Whatever you say.
Can I ask you just one question?
What is that is exactly the same
about every single vacation
you have ever taken?
I give up.
You. You're the same.
No matter where you go, there you are.
It's always the same old you.
Let me suggest that you take
a vacation from yourself.
I know, it sounds wild.
It is the latest thing in travel.
We call it the Ego Trip.
No. I'm not interested in that.
You're gonna love this, Doug.
We offer you a choice of
alternate identities during your trip.
Why go to Mars as a tourist,
when you can go as a playboy?
- Or a famous jock or...?
- "Secret agent."
How much is that?
A-ha! Let me tantalise you.
You are a top operative under deep cover
on your most important mission.
People are trying to kill you.
Left and right!
You meet this beautiful,
exotic woman.
Go on.
I don't wanna spoil it for you, Doug,
but by the time the trip is over,
you get the girl, kill the bad guys
and save the entire planet.
Now, you tell me.
Isn't that worth a measly 300 credits?
(Machine revs up)
- Your first trip?
- Mm-hm.
Well, don't worry. Things hardly ever
fuck up around here.
Good evening... Doug.
- I'm Dr Lull.
- Nice to meet you.
Ernie, patch in matrix 62-B-37.
And would you like us
to integrate some alien stuff?
Sure. Why not?
- Two-headed monsters?
- Don't you keep up with the news?
- We're doing alien artefacts now.
- It's wild.
Yeah, they date back a million years.
- Ernie?
- That's a new one.
- Blue sky on Mars.
- Been married long?
- Eight years.
- Oh, I see.
Slipping away for a little hanky-panky.
- No. I'm fascinated with Mars.
- All systems go.
Then we're set.
- Ready for dreamland?
- (Groans)
I'll be asking you some questions
so we can fine-tune the Ego program.
You answer honestly,
you'll enjoy yourself a whole lot more.
- Your sexual orientation.
- Hetero.
So, how do you like your women?
Blonde? Brunette? Redhead?
Brunette.
Slim. Athletic. Voluptuous.
Athletic.
Demure. Aggressive. Sleazy.
- Be honest.
- Sleazy.
Demure.
41A, Ernie.
Boy, is he gonna have a wild time.
- He's not gonna want to come back.
- Oh, that's for sure.
So...
what do you say?
I'm not so sure,
and I don't get a souvenir.
Not true. For just a few more credits,
we supply T-shirts,
snapshots of you at the site,
and even letters from...
- (Telephone ringing)
- 'Bob!'
- What is it?
- 'You'd better get down here.'
I am with a very important client.
'Looks like we got
another schizoid embolism.'
- I'll be right back.
- Uh... Mr McClane?
- Mr McClane?
- Bob! What's wrong?
Don't let her leave!
(Groaning)
Get off!
Ah!
You blew my cover!
What's going on? You can't do
a simple goddamn double implant?
It's not my fault we hit a memory cap.
They'll be here any minute!
They'll kill you all!
- What is he talking about?
- Let me go!
Mr Quaid, try to calm down!
My name is not Quaid.
- Let me go! Untie me now!
- Ernie, grab his leg!
- Untie me!
- Hold him down!
Let me go!
(Groans)
Ah!
Are you all right?
Listen to me.
He's been going on and on about Mars.
- He has really been there.
- Use your head, you dumb bitch.
He's just acting out the "secret agent"
portion of his ego trip.
- I'm afraid that's not possible.
- Why not?
Because we haven't implanted it yet.
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit!
I've been trying to tell you,
someone has erased his memory.
Excuse me. "Someone"?
We're talking about the fucking Agency.
- Shut up!
- Bob, the client's gone.
OK, all right. All right, look.
Here's what we're going to do.
Renata, cover up any memory
he's got of us or Recall.
I'll do what I can.
It's pretty messy in there.
Ernie, dump him in a cab around
the corner. Tiffany, you help him.
I'm gonna destroy his file
and refund his money.
And if anybody comes asking,
we never heard of Douglas Quaid.
(Driver whistles)
Where am I?
- You're in a Johnnycab.
- What am I doing here?
I'm sorry. Would you please
rephrase the question?
How did I get in this taxi?
The door opened, you got in.
Hell of a day, isn't it?
- This OK?
- Right here.
- Thank you for taking Johnnycab.
- Thank you.
Hope you enjoyed the ride.
Hey, Quaid.
- Harry.
- How was your trip to Mars?
- What trip?
- You went to Recall. Remember?
- I did?
- Yeah, you did.
- I told you not to, but you went anyway.
- What are you, my father?
- Come on, I'll buy you a drink.
- Listen. I'm already late. Thank you...
OK, bring him...
Come on, move it!
Let's go get that drink. Move it!
What the hell is going on?
What the fuck did I do wrong?
- Tell me!
- You blabbed about Mars!
Are you crazy? I don't even know
anything about Mars!
You should've listened to me, Quaid.
I was there to keep you out of trouble.
You're making a big mistake. You got me
mixed up with somebody else.
Uh-uh, pal.
You got yourself mixed up with...
Ah!
(Groaning)
(Bones cracking)
Ah!
(Machine) 'And pivot... and serve...
'and shift... and stroke... and pivot.
'And serve... and shift... and stroke.
'Very good. Perfect form.
'And serve... and shift... and stroke.'
Hi, honey.
- What are you doing?
- Some men just tried to kill me.
Muggers? Are you all right?
No, they were spies or something.
And Harry from work, he was the...
Get down!
- Harry from work, he was the boss.
- Take it easy, Doug, OK?
Tell me exactly what happened.
Why would spies want to kill you?
I don't know.
But it had something to do with Mars.
You've never been to Mars.
It sounds crazy, but I went
to this Recall place after work...
- You went to those brain butchers?
- Let me finish.
- What did they do to you?
- I got a trip to Mars.
- So what happened...
- Oh...
Forget about Recall. Will you?
These guys were going to kill me.
- Doug, nobody tried to kill you.
- They did.
But I killed them.
Listen to me, sweetheart.
Those assholes at Recall
have fucked up your mind.
You're having paranoid delusions.
You call this a delusion?
Doug.
- Doug, I'm gonna call a doctor.
- Don't. Don't call anybody.
'Hello.'
(Grunts)
Lori, go! Get out!
(Gun clicks empty)
(Groans)
- (Panting)
- Lori?
Why are you doing this, Lori?
Talk! I said talk.
- I'm not your wife.
- The hell you're not.
I never saw you
before six weeks ago.
Our marriage is just a memory implant.
You think I'm stupid?
I remember our wedding.
It was implanted by the Agency.
- Falling in love.
- Implanted.
Our friends, my job, 8 years together.
All of this was implanted too?
The job's real.
The Agency set it up.
Bullshit.
They erased your identity
and implanted a new one.
I was written in as your wife
so I could watch you
and make sure the erasure took.
Sorry, Quaid.
Your whole life is just a dream.
OK, then if I'm not me,
who the hell am I?
Beats me.
I just work here.
Doug.
Doug, there's something I want you to know.
You were the best assignment
I ever had. Really.
I'm honoured.
You sure you don't want to,
just for old times' sake?
Come on. If you don't trust me,
you can tie me up.
- I didn't know you were so kinky.
- Maybe it's time you found out.
Clever girl.
You wouldn't shoot me, would you,
Doug? After all we've been through.
Some of it was fun.
Nice knowing you.
Don't touch her.
(Man) Nobody here.
- Are you OK?
- I guess I blew it.
- What does he remember?
- Nothing, so far.
I've got him.
(Device beeping)
Shit, he's going for the subway.
Let's get him. Go.
Let's go. Move it.
Pack your stuff and get outta here.
What if they bring him back?
Not a chance.
Subway! Go!
(Woman) Hey!
(Alarm beeps)
Get him! He's got a gun!
- Cut him off! That way!
- Over there!
- Hold it!
- Don't move!
(Woman screaming)
- (Device beeps)
- The escalator.
You four go up.
You come with me.
Get out of the way! Come on!
Get out of the way! Move!
(People screaming)
The platform!
- Which way?
- To the right.
(TV) 'Botco. Tomorrow's fuels,
tomorrow's prices.
'Don't settle for pale memories
or fake implants.
'Experience space travel
the old-fashioned way
'on a real, live holiday
you can afford.'
I want that fucker dead.
I don't blame you. I wouldn't want
Quaid porking my old lady.
- You saying she likes it?
- No, I'm sure she hated every minute.
(Phone ringing)
(Radio) 'Six-beta-nine, we have
a live transmission from Mr Cohaagen.'
- Richter here. Patch it through.
- 'You're on, Mr Cohaagen.'
- 'What the fuck is going on?'
- I'm trying to neutralise a traitor, sir.
'If I wanted him dead, you moron,
I wouldn't have dumped him on Earth.'
We can't let him run around.
He knows too much.
'Lori says
he can't remember jack shit.'
That's now. In an hour
he could have total recall.
'Listen to me, Richter. I want Quaid
delivered alive for re-implantation.
'Have you got that?
'I want him back in place with Lori.
- 'Did you hear me?'
- (Video crackles)
What was that, sir?
I couldn't hear you.
- 'Richter, what are you doing?'
- (Whispers) I got Quaid again.
Switching to another channel, sir.
I've got sunspots.
(Laughter)
- 'Call him back! Call him back!'
- I'm losing you.
- Where is he?
- Second level, galleria.
We should've killed Quaid on Mars.
- How we doing?
- Fine.
Zooming in... We got him!
(Telephone rings)
(Phone keeps ringing)
'If you want to live, don't hang up.'
- What do you want?
- 'They've got you bugged.'
'They'll be busting down your door
in about three minutes
'unless you do exactly what I say.
'Don't bother searching.
The bug's in your skull.
- Who are you?
- 'Never mind.'
'Wet a towel and wrap it around
your head. That'll muffle the signal.'
- How'd you find me?
- 'I'd advise you to hurry.'
This'll buy you some time.
They won't be able to pinpoint you.'
- (Alarm beeps)
- Shit!
- What?
- I lost him.
- Well, find him!
- Yeah, right.
'Come on. Hurry up.
You look beautiful.
'Now go to the window. Go.
- 'Can you see me down here?'
- Mm-hm.
- 'This is the suitcase you gave me.'
- I gave you?
'I'm gonna set it here.
You come and get it, keep moving.'
- Wait. Wait.
- 'What?'
- Who are you?
- 'We were buddies in the Agency.
'You asked me, if you disappeared,
to find you, so here I am.'
What was I doing on Mars? Damn!
Excuse me, ma'am, but this is mine.
- I don't see your name on it.
- Someone left it for me.
- Find your own bag.
- Excuse me, ma'am, but I need it!
Fuck you, you asshole!
Son of a bitch gotta be here somewhere.
(Richter) That guy there.
Hello, I'm Johnnycab.
Where can I take you tonight?
(Horns blaring)
Drive. Drive!
- Please repeat the destination.
- Anywhere! Just go! Go! Go!
Please state the street and number.
Shit. Shit!
I'm not familiar with that address.
Would you please repeat...?
Fasten your seat belt!
The fare is 18 credits, please.
Sue me, dickhead.
Ah!
We hope you enjoyed the ride.
(Mice squeaking)
Hmm.
(Beeps and crackles)
'Howdy, stranger.
This is Hauser.
'If things have gone wrong,
I'm talking to myself
'and you've got a wet towel
wrapped around your head.
'Now, whatever your name is,
get ready for the big surprise.
'You are not you. You are me.'
No shit.
(Radio) 'Six-beta-nine,
six-beta-nine, come in.'
Did you find him?
'We picked up an explosion
at the old cement factory.'
- Send two units. We'll meet you there.
- 'Roger.'
'All my life I've worked
for Mars Intelligence.
'I did Cohaagen's dirty work.
'But a few weeks ago
I met somebody, a woman,
'and I learned a few things.
'Like I've been playing for the wrong team.
'All I can do now is try to make up for it.
'There's enough shit in here
to fuck Cohaagen good.
'Unfortunately, if you're listening to this,
that means he has got to me first.
'Here comes the hard part,
old buddy.
'Now it is all up to you.'
Great.
- What have we got?
- Nothing here.
- He's gone.
- I got a weak signal over there.
Split up. Find him.
'First let's get rid
of that bug in your head.
'Take this thing out of the case
and stick it up your nose.
'Don't worry. It's self-guiding.
'Just shove real hard.'
(Breathes deeply)
(Groans)
'When it crunches, you're there.
'Just pull it out.
'Be careful. It's my head too.'
Ah! Ah!
- I've got a lock.
- Up. Let's go.
'This is the plan.
'Get your ass to Mars,
'then go to the Hilton and flash
the Brubaker ID at the desk.
'That's all there's to it.
'Just do what I tell you.
'And we can nail that son of the bitch
who fucked you and me.
'I'm counting on you, buddy.
'Don't let me down.'
(Squeaking)
Straight ahead.
In there.
There!
- (Device beeps)
- There!
There!
What? Give me that.
(Hauser) 'Get your ass to Mars.'
- 'Get your ass to Mars.'
- Shit.
'Get your ass to Mars...
Get your ass to Mars...'
(Tannoy) 'Welcome to the Mars
Federal Colony.
'For your safety and comfort,
domes have been installed
'to protect you from the vacuum outside.
'Please do not touch
exterior windows or air locks.
'Air volume is limited. No smoking
is allowed anywhere in the colony.'
Next.
'Thank you,
and enjoy your stay on Mars.'
Passport.
Hmm?
(Man) Get out of the way.
Make way! Stand back!
Mr Cohaagen wants to see you right away.
Any news of Quaid?
- Not since you lost him.
- Watch your mouth, Captain...
- So how long do you plan to stay?
- Two weeks.
Look at that shit.
- What the hell's this?
- The Martians love Kuato.
They think he's fuckin' George Washington.
Kill the bastard.
Nobody knows who he is.
Have you brought any fruits or vegetables?
Two weeks.
Excuse me?
Two weeks!
(Groaning)
It's not just graffiti. The rebels
took over the refinery last night.
No terbinium is going out.
And it gets worse.
T-w-o...
(Groaning)
Quaid.
- That's Quaid!
- Where?
The woman!
Get him... her!
Arrest that woman!
Get that woman. Grab her!
Catch!
Get ready for a surprise!
(Hissing)
(Wind blowing)
(Screaming)
(Screams)
Ah!
- Open the goddamn door!
- I can't!
Open it!
They're all connected!
That's terrible.
A few days ago
Cohaagen raised the price of air.
Again?
Nobody on Earth gives a damn
what happens up here.
They just want our terbinium
so they can fight their war.
Excuse me. What's that?
You mean the Pyramid Mine?
I used to work there until
they found that alien shit inside.
Well, that's a rumour, isn't it?
Think so?
Mr Cohaagen.
You wanted to see me, sir?
Richter...
Do you know why I'm such a happy person?
No, sir.
Because I've got the greatest job
in the solar system.
As long as the terbinium keeps flowing,
I can do anything I want.
Anything.
In fact, the only thing
that I ever worry about
is that one day, if the rebels win,
it all might end...
and you're fucking making it happen!
First you try to kill Quaid,
then you let him get away.
He had help from our side, sir.
I know that.
- But I thought...
- Who told you to think?
I don't give you enough information
to think.
You do what you're told.
That's what you do.
Yes, sir.
Now...
Let's get to business.
We've got a tricky situation here.
Kuato wants what's in Quaid's head.
And he might be able to get it,
cos they say he's psychic.
And I have a plan
to keep this from happening.
Do you think you could play along?
- Yes, sir.
- Great.
Cos otherwise, I'll erase your ass.
(Officer) You've got some
identification? Yeah, you too.
Taxi? You need a taxi, sir?
I got magazines, music, whisky.
Hey, man, you need a cab, man?
Come on! Come on!
(Indistinct chatter)
Good afternoon. Can I help you?
Yes, I would like to have a room, please.
Nice to have you back, Mr Brubaker.
Would you like the same suite?
Oh, definitely.
Seems you've left something in our safe.
Could you get it, please?
Identification?
- I'll encode your room key.
- Thank you.
- Suite 610 in the east wing.
- Could I borrow your pen, please?
- Certainly.
Thank you.
Hey, man, you need a cab?
- What's wrong with this one?
- He ain't got five kids to feed.
- Where's yours?
- Right over there, man.
Hey! Hey, man.
Hey, asshole! That's my fare!
- Eat this!
- Damn you, Benny!
(Explosion and screaming)
Welcome to Mars, man!
What the hell was that, an accident?
That's the rebels, man.
Let's get outta here...
Before they arrest us!
What do the rebels want?
The usual.
More money, more freedom, more air.
So, where to?
Last Resort.
You're getting off to an early start.
- First time on Mars?
- Yes.
Well, actually, no. Well, sort of.
(Laughs) The man don't even know
whether he's been to Mars or not.
(Metallic rattling)
Voila. Venusville.
Ha, ha!
Hey, you see anything you like?
Well, this is the end of the line.
We'd better walk from here.
I'll show you where.
- Do you want to know the future?
- What about the past?
Come on. It's around the corner,
right down this alley.
They got everything.
Not bad, huh?
Read your palm? Your mind? Your aura?
Probe the secrets of your heart?
I bet I can guess your birthday.
- You're a Taurus, right?
- How did you guess?
- Tell me, are all psychics...?
- Freaks?
Afraid so, man.
It goes with the territory.
- What happened to them?
- Cheap domes, no air to clean the rays.
So, this is it. The Last Resort.
You sure you want to go in here?
- Why not?
- There's a better place down there.
The girls are cleaner,
the liquor ain't watered down...
- Sure, and you get kickbacks.
- (Laughs)
Hey, man, I got five kids to feed.
Take them to the dentist.
Hey, thanks, mister!
I'll be waiting for you.
You just take your time.
Benny's the name.
(Upbeat music playing)
- What do you want?
- I'm looking for Melina.
She's busy.
But Mary here, she's free.
Well, not free, honey, but...
...available.
Ha-ha-ha!
Thanks. I'll wait for Melina.
Earth slime.
Thing is, friend, Mel's real picky.
She kind of sticks to her regulars.
She'll like me.
Mel!
- Hey, Mel!
- (Laughter)
Hello, Hauser.
Still bulging, I see.
(Groans)
- What you been feeding this thing?
- Blondes.
I think it's still hungry.
You got a lot of nerve
showing your face around here, Hauser.
Look who's talking.
Hey, Tony,
give the big guy a break.
Relax. You'll live longer.
Come on.
- Honey, take care of Tony, will you?
- No problem.
If you need any help with this one,
give me a holler.
You son of a bitch.
You're alive? I thought that
Cohaagen tortured you to death.
Well, I guess he didn't.
And you couldn't get me a message? You
never wondered what happened to me?
Hauser, thank God you're alive.
Melin... Melina. Melina.
- Melina, I have to tell you something.
- What?
- I don't remember you.
- What are you talking about?
I don't remember you.
I don't remember us.
I don't even remember me.
Did you get amnesia?
How did you get here?
- Hauser left me a note.
- Hauser? You're Hauser.
Not anymore.
Now I'm Quaid. Douglas Quaid.
- Hauser, you've lost your mind.
- I didn't. Cohaagen stole it.
He found out that Hauser switched sides,
so he turned him into somebody else: me.
This is too weird.
He dumped me on earth
with a wife and a lousy job...
Did you say wife?
Are you fucking married?
- She wasn't really my wife.
- Oh, she isn't?
How stupid of me.
She was Hauser's wife?
- Look. Forget that I said wife.
- Let's just forget everything.
- I'm sick of hearing your goddamn lies.
- Why would I lie to you?
Because you're still working for Cohaagen.
Don't be ridiculous.
You never loved me, Hauser.
You just used me to get inside.
Inside what?
I think you'd better leave.
- Hauser sent me to do something.
- I'm not falling for it.
He says there's enough in here
to nail Cohaagen for good.
- Get out!
- You've got to help me remember!
- I said, get out!
- Melina, please!
People are trying to kill me.
Really?
All right, I'm leaving.
(Benny chuckles)
Baby, you make me wish
I had three hands.
I think you're doing just fine with two.
Excuse me, baby.
We'll pick this up later.
Hey, that didn't take long.
Listen. Let me ask you a question.
Did you ever fuck a mutant?
- Take me to the hotel.
- I know these Siamese twins.
Man, you won't know
if you're coming or going.
'This afternoon at 4:30pm,
I signed an order declaring martial law
'throughout the Mars federal colony.
'I will not tolerate any further damage
to our mineral export operations.
'Mr Kuato and his terrorists
must understand
'that their self-defeating efforts
will only bring misery and suffering...'
(Knocks on door)
- (Man) Mr Quaid?
- What?
I need to talk to you about Mr Hauser.
- Who are you?
- Dr Edgemar from Recall.
- How did you find me?
- It's difficult to explain.
Could you open the door?
I'm unarmed.
Don't worry. I'm alone.
May I come in?
What do you want?
This is going to be very difficult
for you to accept, Mr Quaid.
- I'm listening.
- You're not really standing here now.
- Doc, you could have fooled me.
- I'm quite serious.
You're not here and neither am I.
That's amazing.
- Where are we?
- At Recall.
You're strapped into an implant chair,
and I'm monitoring you
from the psychoprobe console.
Ah, I get it. I'm dreaming.
And all this is part of the delightful
vacation your company has sold me.
Not exactly.
What you're experiencing is a free-form
delusion based on our memory tapes
but you're inventing it yourself
as you go along.
If it is my delusion,
who the hell invited you?
I've been artificially implanted
as an emergency measure.
I'm sorry to tell you this,
but you've suffered a schizoid embolism.
We can't snap you out of your fantasy,
and I've been sent in
to try to talk you down.
How much is Cohaagen paying you for this?
Think about it. Your dream started
in the middle of the implant procedure.
Everything after that,
the chases, the trip to Mars,
the suite at the Hilton, are elements
of your Recall Holiday and Ego Trip.
You paid to be a secret agent.
Bullshit. It's coincidence.
And what about the girl?
Brunette, athletic,
sleazy and demure?
Just as you specified.
Is that coincidence?
She's real. I dreamt about her
before I even went to Recall.
Ha, Mr Quaid.
Can you hear yourself?
She's real because you dreamed her?
- That's right.
- Maybe this will convince you.
Would you mind opening the door?
- You open it.
- No need to be rude. I'll do it.
Sweetheart?
Come in, Mrs Quaid.
- I suppose you're not here either.
- I'm here...at Recall.
I love you.
Right.
That's why you tried to kill me.
No. I'd never do anything
to hurt you.
I want you to come back to me.
- Bullshit.
- What's bullshit, Mr Quaid?
That you're having a paranoid episode
triggered by acute neurochemical trauma?
Or that you're really an invincible
secret agent from Mars,
who's the victim of an interplanetary
conspiracy to make him think
he's a lowly construction worker?
Stop punishing yourself, Doug.
You're a fine, upstanding man.
You have a beautiful wife who loves you.
- Your whole life is ahead of you.
- I do.
But you've got to want
to return to reality.
Let's assume I do. Then what?
- Swallow this.
- What is it?
It's a symbol of your desire
to return to reality.
Inside your dream, you'll fall asleep.
All right, let's say you're telling
the truth and this is all a dream.
Then I could pull this trigger
and it won't matter.
- Doug, don't.
- It won't make a difference to me.
But the consequences to you would be
devastating. In your mind I'll be dead.
With no one to guide you out,
you'll be stuck in permanent psychosis.
Doug, let Dr Edgemar help you.
The walls of reality
will come crashing down.
One minute you'll be
the saviour of the rebel cause,
and the next thing you know
you'll be Cohaagen's bosom buddy.
You'll even have fantasies about
alien civilisations, as you requested,
but in the end, back on earth
you'll be lobotomised!
So get a grip on yourself, Doug,
and put down that gun!
Good. Now take the pill
and put it in your mouth.
Swallow it!
Go ahead, sweetheart.
Now you've done it.
Now you've done it!
(Groaning)
Ah!
Aargh!
That's for making me come to Mars.
You know how much I hate
this fucking planet!
Cuff him.
- 'I got him.'
- Bring him down in the service elevator.
Let's go.
(Grunts)
(Lift bell rings)
(Beeping)
(Beeps)
Fuck you!
(Gunshot)
Doug.
Honey...
You wouldn't hurt me,
would you, sweetheart?
Sweetheart, be reasonable.
After all, we're married.
Consider that a divorce.
That was your wife?
What a bitch.
(Beeping)
Hey, get out of the way!
I thought you didn't like me.
If Cohaagen wants you dead,
you might be OK.
- Got it.
- So you've come back to apologise.
Kuato wants to see you.
(Beeping)
Come on.
- Now what?
- Jump!
Ah!
(Grunts)
No! Don't do it!
You'll crack the fucking dome!
What are you trying to do, kill us?
The dome will crack!
- Move!
- Hey!
Taxi!
Melina! Melina!
- Need a ride?
- Last Resort. Quick!
You guys are going in circles.
Jesus!
Come on! You drive!
You guys are in trouble?
Go! Go!
- What are you trying to do to me?
- Shut up and drive!
Hey, I got five kids to feed!
Aargh!
Shit!
- No brakes! Ah!
- Stop it!
You idiot!
What are you doing?
(People screaming)
Oh, Christ! Now they're after me!
Give me that!
Get out of the way!
Hey!
Tony!
Get out of the way!
Come on!
Come on! Come on!
Quick!
- Thank you, Tony.
- Uh-um.
(People screaming)
Hey! You wanna have some fun?
Where are they?
What are you talking about?
I don't know.
(Screaming)
Maybe you know.
Kill them all!
(Screaming)
Ah!
Thumbelina!
Richter!
- A call from Cohaagen!
- Richter here.
- We've got them pinned down.
- 'Stop fighting and pull out.'
But they've got Quaid.
They're protecting him.
'Perfect.
Get out of Sector G now.
'Don't think.'
- 'Do it!'
- Yes, sir.
Pull 'em out.
Everybody, pull out!
Move!
- Cohaagen's sealing off the area!
- Come on, Benny!
(Groans)
The first settlers are buried here.
They worked themselves to death, but
Cohaagen ended up with all the money.
He built cheap domes and
watched the kids turn into freaks.
I saw them.
And if you want to breathe,
you have to buy his air.
Maybe you can change all that.
(Benny) Hey, I think my grandpa
might be here.
So what can I do?
Kuato's gonna make you remember some
things you knew when you were Hauser.
- Like what?
- All sorts of things.
- Maybe you'll remember you loved me.
- I don't need Kuato for that.
Since when?
Freeze!
Come on, Melina.
Kuato's waiting.
I didn't find Grandpa, but...
Oh, shit.
- Who's this?
- He helped us get away.
Hey, don't worry about me, man.
I'm on your side.
You're a mutant, huh?
All right, let's go.
- Have you tried ramming down the door?
- You wait here. Follow me.
(Mutant) 'It won't do any good.
- 'Cohaagen depressurised the tunnels.'
- Then drill through to Section M.
'We can't.
We're running out of air.
'We need help.'
Sit tight.
Melina just got here with Quaid.
'I hope he was worth it.'
So do I.
- I'm glad you made it.
- You don't look glad.
Cohaagen sealed up Venusville.
He shut off the air.
You must know something
pretty important, Quaid.
He wants you.
If we don't hand you over, everybody
in this sector will be dead by morning.
Then we don't have much choice.
Do we?
We can't turn him in.
That's up to Kuato.
Come with me, Quaid.
Sit down.
- Where's Kuato?
- On his way.
You heard the rumours
about the Pyramid Mine?
Yeah.
Cohaagen found something weird inside
and it's got him scared shitless.
What? Aliens?
- You tell me.
- I don't know.
Yes, you do.
That's why we brought you here.
Cohaagen's big secret
is buried in that black hole
you call a brain.
And Kuato's gonna dig it out.
- You're Kuato, right?
- Wrong.
Kuato's a mutant,
so don't get upset when you see him.
Ah!
What do you want, Mr Quaid?
The same as you. To remember.
But why?
- To be myself again.
- You are what you do.
A man is defined by his actions...
not his memory.
Please take my hands.
Ah!
Now open your mind to me.
Please.
Open your mind.
We should blow the thing up
before the rebels turn it on.
I say we throw the switch
and see what happens.
- Don't be an idiot.
- We can't risk it.
The chain reaction could spread
to all the terbinium in the planet.
That means a meltdown,
a meltdown on a planetary scale.
Don't you think whoever
built this thing thought of that?
Who knows what the hell they thought?
They weren't human.
Maybe it's a trap.
Maybe they want a meltdown.
We don't even know
if this piece of junk will work.
What is it?
A million? Half a million?
- About half a million.
- Half a million years old.
Let's make sure Kuato...
(Heavy rumbling)
Wake up! Wake up!
Come on, wake up!
They found us! Shit! Let's go!
Wake up! Snap out of it now!
Come on!
- They found us! Everybody out!
- Melina!
(Kuato) Get moving! Get out!
Get out!
Everybody out! Get out!
Get to the air lock! Follow me!
Benny, come on!
- Benny!
- I'm coming!
- Ah!
- This way!
Put these spacesuits on!
We're going outside!
Benny, hurry.
Congratulations, Quaid.
You led us right to him.
How can you do this?
You're a mutant.
- I got four kids to feed.
- So what happened to number five?
(Laughs) Oh, shit, man. You got me.
I ain't even married.
Now put your fucking hands in the air!
(Kuato) Quaid.
Quaid.
Forget it, man.
His fortunetelling days are over.
Start the reactor.
Free Mars.
(Gunshot)
Mr Cohaagen would like to talk to you.
So this is the great man.
No wonder he kept out of sight.
Well, my boy...
- You're a hero.
- Fuck you.
Uh? Don't be modest.
Kuato is dead.
The resistance is completely wiped out,
and you were the key to the whole thing.
He's lying.
You two-faced bastard.
Ha, ha. You can't blame him, angel.
He's innocent.
You see, Quaid, none of my people
could get close to Kuato.
Fucking mutants could always sniff us out.
So Hauser and I sat down
and invented you, the perfect mole.
You know you're lying.
Hauser turned against you.
That's what we wanted you to think.
The fact is, Hauser volunteered
to become Doug Quaid.
It was the only way to fool the psychics.
Get your story straight.
This idiot here has been trying to kill me
ever since I went to Recall.
You don't kill somebody
you're trying to plant.
He wasn't in on it.
You set him off by going to Recall.
- So why am I still alive?
- We gave you lots of help.
- Benny here.
- My pleasure, man.
The guy with the suitcase,
the mask, the money,
the message from Hauser,
all of that was set up by us.
Sorry. Too perfect.
Perfect, my ass!
You pop your memory cap
before we can activate you.
Richter goes hog-wild, screwing up
everything I spent a year planning.
Frankly, I'm amazed it worked.
Well, Cohaagen,
I have to hand it to you.
It's the best mind-fuck yet.
Well, don't take my word for it.
- Someone you trust wants to talk to you.
- Who is it this time? My mother?
'Howdy, Quaid.
'If you're listening to this,
it means that Kuato is dead
'and you have led us to him.
'I knew you wouldn't let me down.
'Sorry for the shit I've put you through,
but hey, what are friends for?
'I would like to wish you
happiness and long life, old buddy,
'but unfortunately,
this is not gonna happen.
'You see, it's my body
you've got there and I want it back.
'Sorry to be an Indian giver,
but I was here first.
'So adios, amigo.
'And thanks for not
getting yourself killed.
'Hey, maybe we'll meet in our dreams.
'You never know.'
(Quaid) You bastards!
Let go of me!
(Man #1) Ready?
(Man #2) Auto.
- Check.
- Ready to go, sir.
Relax, Quaid.
- You'll like being Hauser.
- The guy's a fucking asshole.
Not true.
He's one of my best friends.
Besides, he's got
a big house and a Mercedes.
And you like Melina, right?
You'll get to fuck her every night.
That's right.
She's going to be Hauser's babe.
I'll bust his balls.
Uh-uh, princess.
We're having you fixed.
You're going to be respectful, compliant
and appreciative,
the way a woman should be.
Mr Cohaagen, telephone.
Yes? What is it?
'The oxygen level
is bottoming out in Sector G.
'What do you want me
to do about it?'
- Don't do anything.
- 'But they won't last an hour, sir.'
Fuck 'em. It'll be a good lesson
to the others.
Come on, you got what you want.
Give these people air.
My friend, in five minutes
you won't give a shit about the people.
Fire it up, Doc.
Excuse me, Doctor.
- Is he gonna remember any of this?
- Not a thing.
Oh, really?
Quaid, I'm having a party tonight.
Why don't you and Melina drop by?
- Remind him, Doc.
- Sure.
See you at the party.
Keep still.
Fighting just makes it hurt.
If you don't keep still,
you'll end up psychotic.
Hey, don't!
Melina, hold on!
Are you all right?
Are you still you?
I'm not sure, dear.
What do you think?
Let's get the hell out of here.
You have to make a decision, sir.
Kill him.
It's about goddamn time.
- Where are you going?
- To the reactor.
- What reactor?
- The one in the mines. Come on!
People are dying, Quaid!
Stop! We've got to get air!
The reactor makes air.
That's Cohaagen's secret. Let's go.
Where's this reactor come from?
- Aliens built it.
- Aliens?
- Are you sure about this?
- It's just up ahead.
What the hell?
Quaid! Hey, Quaid,
you remember me?
Benny! Benny's the name!
Oh, that's good!
I'm gonna drill you, sucker!
I'm gonna grind you up!
Ha-ha! I'm coming!
I'm coming for you, baby!
What the fuck is this?
Damn this piece of Martian junk!
Hey, Quaid,
I'm gonna squash you!
Benny, here!
Where the fuck are you?
Screw you!
- Quaid, get over here!
- What is it?
- There's an opening.
- I knew it.
This whole thing is one big reactor
made out of terbinium.
Cohaagen knows it makes air.
The bastard won't turn it on.
Of course not. If Mars had
an atmosphere, he'd lose control.
See down there?
It's a glacier.
The whole core of Mars is ice.
The reactor melts it
and it releases the oxygen.
Come on.
- Enough for everyone to breathe?
- Sure.
Enough for the whole planet.
If we turn it on in time.
Come on. Come on!
Hold on.
Now!
Son of a bitch.
Move!
He's got a hologram!
You think this is
the real Quaid? It is.
You're coming with me!
See you at the party, Richter.
- Don't touch that! Get back!
- What are you afraid of?
- Turn it on.
- Impossible!
Once the reaction starts, it'll spread
to all the terbinium in the planet.
Mars will go into global meltdown.
That's why the aliens never turned it on.
And you expect me to believe you?
Who gives a shit what you believe?
In 30 seconds you'll be dead.
Then I'll blow this place up
and be home in time for cornflakes.
I didn't want it to end this way.
I wanted Hauser back. But no.
You had to be Quaid!
- I am Quaid.
- You're nothing!
You're nobody!
You're a stupid dream.
Well, all dreams come to an end.
Melina, hold on!
Don't do it! We'll all die!
Everybody will die!
Quaid!
(Gasping and groaning)
(Distant, low rumbling)
I can't believe it.
It's like a dream.
What's wrong?
I just had a terrible thought.
What if this is a dream?
Well, then kiss me quick
before you wake up.